Rick Troemel 1965 Picadilly Dr Sierra Vista, AZ 85635 +15205083532 Cell

rick@codebearsoftware.com

Jitterbit/WebService Skills:

I have been working with Jitterbit for 5+ years, and have worked with both Jitterbit Studio as well as Jitterbit Cloud Studio and have used both with local as well as cloud agents. I have worked on Jitterbit integrations with Microsoft D365, Concur, and Salesforce and some Home Grown Applications et al.

In addition, I have 20 years experience developing client applications for both SOAP and RESTFul Web Services using various programming environments, and can speak both XML and json fluently. I have in fact made a career out of connecting disparate systems (usually with web services). I am also thoroughly familiar with WS modeling and debugging tools like Postman and Fiddler.

Work Experience:

Jitterbit Developer (Remote Contract) Clipper Magazine Ephrata, PA September 2023 - Present

This is a side contract for 5-10 hours per week, primarily on weekends. The work is developing and maintaining connections between Clipper's home grown ERP system and Salesforce. The Jitterbit connector architecture was to have the source system write the data to be updated to a SQL database, then the JB scripts read the SQL database, transform the data to a format understood by the target and updates the target. The bulk of Clipper's integrations are ERP system to SFDC, so the ERP writes to the database, JB reads the records needing updating, then updates SFDC are performed using Web Services via the built in SFDC "widget". For SFDC to the ERP, Jitterbit reads the SFDC tables directly using SOQL queries and updates the ERP system by writing directly to its SQL tables. This work is all in Jitterbit Studio and using a local agent. We are presently wrapping up the last project and I will be rolling off this contract in the next few weeks.

Senior Applications Developer, SFDC Pingwind.
Anandale, VA (Remote)

July 2023 - Present

Pingwind does contract development for the Veteran's Administration. Developing new systems to track Time and Performance Data for Employees. Flows, Security/Access, Reports, Dashboards, Custom Object development. Deployment using MS Code, SFDX and GitHub.

Senior Applications Developer Impini

Feb 2018 – May 2023

Seattle, WA

Impinj is a provider of RAIN RFID chips and readers, which are used in a variety of IOT (Internet of Things) applications. Duties at Impinj included SFDC development, Jitterbit (a middleware platform similar to Mulesoft) and Microsoft Power Automate integration development as well as some Workday Studio development. Most of these efforts were to connect SFDC, Concur, Workday, ADP, Microsoft AX and Microsoft D365 with each other. Initially, I inherted existing Jitterbit connectors which were written using Jitterbit Studio, and converted these to Cloud Studio projects using the Cloud Agent.

These connectors were between Concur, SFDC, and Microsoft AX. Later, Impinj upgraded MS AX to MS D365, and I authored the connector between Concur expenses entered by employees with D365 and a new connector using JB Cloud Studio to connect D365 with Impinj's Warehouse provider shipping chips and readers to clients. Near the end of my tenure with Imping, we were actually moving away from Jitterbit to re-implement the existing connectors using MS Power Automate, which is capable of the pretty much same operations and was cheaper for Impinj, as PA was part of the D365 subscription. Lastly, I was also one of the administrators for Impinj's HR and payroll system, ADP.

Salesforce Integration Developer

Aug 2016 – Feb 2018

Workday

Pleasanton, CA

Responsible for Workday's Salesforce Integration. Responsible for maintenance and improvement of an existing legacy application which synchronizes SFDC data to the Workday ERP (e.g. Accounts -> Customers, Opportunities->Invoices, etc.). Later added a Workday to Salesforce integration which displays Workday Customer Activity in the user's SFDC Account Page as read only data.

Connector Developer

Jul 2012 - Mar 2016

Avalara

Bainbridge Island, WA

Wrote, maintained and supported connectors for various accounting programs for the Avalara SAAS transactional tax calculation and management service. During my tenure, I was the primary developer for Avalara's SFDC Connector (written in Apex), Zuora Connector (written using ASP.net), and Workday connector (written using Workday Studio). During this time, we also were in progress for an integration to Steelbrick Quotes just after SFDC acquired them. My colleagues completed this integration following my move to Workday.

Developer

Mar 2010 - Mar 2011

Intel

Dupont, WA

Contract Position – initially 4 months, but extended to 1 year. Implementing new features and bug fixing for Intel's "In Target Probe" (ITP) software, written in C++. ITP uses JTAG to assist with design, debug and validation of new computer chips. ITP communicates with the underlying target chip via a Debug Port which is built into the chip design (Design For Debug, DFD) and an ITP "pod" which plugs into the Debug Port on one end and USB on the host computer.

Owner/Developer

Oct 2009 - Jul 2012

CodeBear Software, LLC

Hansville, WA

Self employed. Custom Software/Ecommerce/Cloud Computing/Databases ERP Plugins and Integration Between Disparate Systems. The bulk of my work was doing "One off" custom connectors for Avalara clients via referrals. Also developed and sold (via the App Exchange) an SFDC Apex SDK to make WS calls to the Avalara Service, an integration into SFDC Opportunities, and SFDC native Quotes. Later sold these products to Avalara, who is now giving these apps to clients who want to integrate with SFDC.

Senior Support Analyst / Developer

Support

Feb 2005 - Oct 2009

<u>Avalara</u>

Bainbridge Island, WA

Founding employee of Avalara, Inc. Duties included SDK support/consulting, 2nd tier support for difficult cases that the front line support team was unable to resolve, maintenance of a suite of Virtual Machines with various accounting products installed for use by both the support and QA departments. Also assisted and acted in a consulting role with our plug-in developers and assisted with usability studies / interface specification and design for plug-in software and website tools. Finally, wrote and maintained various custom tools for our support team and select customers (usually in C#), as well as code samples for developer customers using .NET, java and PHP.

SDET
Microsoft Corporation

Oct 2000 - Feb 2005

Redmond, WA

QA for Visual C++ compiler back end (code generation / optimization). Wrote test plans and implemented tests for new features, maintained existing test suite, analyzed test runs which targeted X86, AMD64, and IA64 chipsets. Maintained "Real World Code" builds of NT (Vista) using daily compiler builds. Investigated bug reports from beta customers and developer support. When appropriate, reported the bug to development, worked with developers to correct it and develop new tests for those bugs which uncovered a hole in the test suite.

Second tier Visual C++ compiler, linker, library and integrated development environment support. When initial telephone "helpdesk" support was unable to resolve a customer's issue, it was escalated to us in second tier support. Customers were engaged primarily through telephone callbacks and email. We also moderated and often participated in internet newsgroup "peer to peer" support discussions. Developer Support entailed wearing several hats:

- QA Hat: when a customer's issue involved a product bug, in which case our job was to get a reproducible test case to report to QA, then help the customer find a "workaround" for their problem.
- Consultant Hat: when the issue was a "how-to" question, or a build error caused by incorrect code.
- Tech Writer Hat: We also wrote Knowledge Base articles and samples for MSDN to help fill holes in product documentation, document a bug and its workaround, or explain how to perform common programming tasks in the VC++/Win16/Win32 environments.

Education:

The Evergreen State College Olympia, WA BS Computer Science, 1986

<u>Pierce College</u> Steilacoom, WA AAS Mathematics, 1984

- <u>Linkedin</u>
- Latest Version

References and Earlier Work History available upon request.